Hello welcome to W3C
Have you ever switch your web content
from one language to another
and just find out the text got broken
today I'm going to present W3C's article
Text size in translation
and gonna show you how text size
gonna affect the readability
and accessibility of your web content across languages
so importantly
Let's take China's biggest e-commerce website
Taobao as an example
if you switch into English
you'll find that text wrap
splits a single word into two lines
words get cut off mid sentence
and if you click into this
there is also text run out of space
it's a small visual detail
but it instantly makes your content harder to read
and less trustworthy for international users
and it all comes down to internationalization issues
let's take a closer look
this is an example of a 9 word English sentence
very simple
then we have German Chinese Japanese translations
ideas are the same
but the length of the line is longer or shorter
very differently among both European and
Asian languages
this is the everyday reality of multilingual design
what fits neatly in one language
may just overlap or collapse in another language
Flickr has a great table of the ratio of different
expansion rates across languages
what you're seeing is a comparison
of how the word 'Views'
changes in length when translated into other languages
English just five letters
But translations differ
some stay close to that length
some double or even triple it
300% expansion rate from English to Italian
is not surprising for small strings such as this
and in Koreana and Chinese
the lens is similar but it needs more vertical space
according to IBM's Global Design Guidelines
text usually expands when translated
but here's something interesting
you can see in the table
the shorter the original text
the larger is the expansion is likely to be
so if we don't plan for that growth
we end up with broken interfaces
balance that overflow labels that get cut off
and layouts that simply don't work anymore
we also have other complicating factors
that affect your tax expansion
on your web content page
firstly
a number of languages such as Finnish
German and Dutch
create single
large words to replace
what is a sequence of smaller words
in other languages
for example the English 'input processing features'
may become very very long in German
so in English
that phrase can easily wrap into two lines
when space is tight
but the German version it might not wrap at all
it just keeps going
and that can easily break your layout
then there are languages like Chinese
Japanese and Korean
their characters are more complex than Latin letters
each word takes up more horizontal space
for instance the English word desktop
the Japanese one has only seven characters
but it looks much wider on screen
and vertical space matters too
some scripts such as Thai Arabic and the vernacular
have taller characters
and require more space between lines
in this example
you can see that
the same text in English and Thai
both take up two lines
but the Thai version is noticeably taller
and this just doesn't not only happen with Thai
many scripts including Arabic Chinese
Japanese and Korean
need also extra height for clarity
finally it's about abbreviations
when designing interfaces
we sometimes shorten words to make them fit
but this can cause problems in translation
some languages just don't use them at all
or
they cannot shorten words without changing the meaning
Arabic for instance
builds words using compact root patterns with
prefixes and suffixes
so abbreviating can easily distort their meaning
in general the more flexible your layout is
and the more consideration you have
given to other languages
the better your design will handle the translation
W3C has other articles which go deeper into this topic
including more detailed guidance for web and UI design
here are the links of this content
and you can also find them below this video